推動
Push.
哦，天哪，它來了！
Oh, God, it's coming!
它來了！
It's coming!
哦，天哪，它來了！
Oh, God, it's coming!
我寶貝在哭]
I baby cries]
拜託 請把他給我
Please. Please give him to me.
拜託
Please.
不，求你了，我的寶貝！
No. Please, my baby!
請把他給我
Please give him to me.
[女人哭我
[woman crying I
該死的！
Damn you!
當邁爾斯 六歲的時候，
When Michael Myers was six years old,
他把他妹妹刺死了
he stabbed his sister to death.
他被關了好幾年，
For years, he was locked up,
鎖定 在史密斯格羅夫療養院
locked away in Smith's Grove Sanatorium'
但他逃走了，
But he escaped,
突然間“萬聖節” 是另一個表示混亂的詞
and suddenly "Halloween“ was another word for mayhem.
他需要消滅 他全家
He needed to wipe out his entire family.
他晚上把他們打倒了 總是在萬聖節
He struck them down at night and always on Halloween.
字幕譯製-貝支子-
員警什麼都試過了 阻止他
The police tried everything to stop him.
他戰勝了他們
He overcame them all...
然後消失了
and disappeared.
全世界都認為他死了，
The world thought him dead,
但我——我不確定
but I--l wasn't sure.
我不確定 邁克爾?邁爾斯死了
I wasn't sure that Michael Myers had died.
傑米，過來
Jamie, come to me.
傑米
Jamie.
傑米，跟我來
Jamie, come with me...
如果你想救你的孩子
If you want to save your baby.
天哪，他來了
God, he's coming.
我們現在得走了來吧;
We've got to move now. Come on'
[嬰兒啼哭1
[Baby crying 1
[喘氣我
[gasping I
你能做到的你能做到的
You can do it. You can do it.
在那裡就這樣
There. it's that way.
否
No.
不，救你的孩子
No, save your baby.
快走！走出！
Go! Get out!
傑米？
Jamie?
[嬰兒啼哭1
[Baby crying 1
嘿！你是幹什麼的 對我的卡車幹什麼？！
Hey! What are you doing to my truck?!
到底是什麼 你對我的卡車做了什麼？
What the hell are you doing to my truck?
什麼？！
What?!
請幫我
Please help me get...
什麼？！
What?!
丹尼
Danny.
為他殺人;
Kill for him'
媽媽！
Mommy!
丹尼？
Danny?
媽媽來了
Mommy's here.
怎麼了，寶貝？
What is it, baby?
配音員，他來了
The voice man, he's here.
沒人在，親愛的
No one's there, sweetheart.
但我見過他
But I've seen him'
你一直在看 電視太多了你知道嗎？
You've been watching way too much TV. You know that?
他說了很多壞話
He says things, bad things.
比如什麼？
Like what?
好的-
Okay-
離遠點，怪物們
Stay away, monsters.
走開，食屍鬼
Stay away, ghouls.
離丹尼遠點
Stay away from Danny.
你們這些混蛋知道規矩
You jerks know the rules.
更好？
Better?
在這裡
Here.
晚安，丹尼
Good night, Danny.
晚安，媽媽
Night, Mom.
是“頂嘴” 和巴里?西姆斯在一起
it's "Back Talk" with Barry Simms.
嘿，那傢伙是誰？ 我們在第二個小時
Hey, who is that guy? We're in the second hour
特別的萬聖節 “回話”版
of a special Halloween edition of "Back Talk.“
我是巴里?西姆斯，和往常一樣， 我們是來找你的
I'm Barry Simms, and as usual, We're coming to you live
從西爾斯塔頂的高處 在芝加哥
from high atop the Sears Tower here in Chicago.
明晚，我們會 從哈頓菲爾德來找你，
Tomorrow night, we will be coming to you from Haddonfield,
被禁止的城鎮 1989年的萬聖節，
the town that has banned Halloween since 1989,
當臭名昭著的連環殺手 邁克爾?邁爾斯，
when infamous serial killer Michael Myers,
他的侄女傑米?勞埃德，
his niece Jamie Lloyd,
還有十幾個員警 在一次爆炸中喪生
and about a dozen cops were killed in an explosion.
我們有個來電者在等著
We have a caller waiting.
下一個跟我說話的是誰？
Who's next to talk to me?
呃，我知道 聽起來有點瘋狂，巴里，
Uh, I know this may sound crazy, Barry,
但我真的認為 我愛上他了
but I really think I'm in love with him'
我是說，他--他太沒教養了， 如此不羈
I mean, he--he's so untamed, so uninhibited.
他是一切 我曾經想要一個男人
He's everything I've ever wanted in a man'
你知道，這很好
You know, this is good.
我現在可以看小報了
I can see the tabloids now.
“神經病生了NymphO，
"Psycho Lays NymphO,
最好的性愛 他曾經肢解過”
the best sex he ever dismembers.“
這是那種 你總是喜歡，女士？
Is this the type you always fall for, lady?
任何其他系列螺柱 在名單上？
Any other serial studs on the list?
你知道嗎，邦迪？曼森？
You know, Bundy? Manson?
那怎麼辦-- 那個叫達默的傢伙呢？
What about that-- What about the Dahmer guy?
我打賭——我打賭你真的可以 和他一起做飯，不是嗎？
I bet--l bet you could really cook with him, couldn't you?
不，我只想要邁克爾
No. I just want Michael.
我想知道 面具後面是什麼
I want to know what's behind that mask.
在內心深處，我認為他 就像你和我一樣，巴里
Deep down, I think he's just like you and me, Barry.
他只是需要一個人 為了理解他，
He just needs someone to understand him,
有人愛他
someone to love him'
是啊在內心深處，我--
Yeah. Deep down, I'm--
是的，我肯定那是真的
Yeah, I'm sure that's true.
你知道，你在說
You know, you're talking about
這個國家的 最臭名昭著的連環殺手
one of this nation's most notorious serial killers
就像他屬於 在某種est研討會上
like--like he belongs in some kind of an est seminar.
你知道，我不想成為那個 告訴你這個消息，女士，
You know, I hate to be the one to break the news to you, lady,
但邁爾斯已經死了 六年了
but Michael Myers has been dead for six years.
現在我們有人了 實際上聲稱
Now we've got someone who actually claims
看到 邁克爾?邁爾斯
to have seen that Michael Myers.
這個古怪的來電者 有名字嗎？
Does this wacko caller have a name?
我叫湯米
My name's Tommy.
我才八歲 當我看到他時，
I was only eight years old when I saw him,
但我是幸運兒之一
but I was one of the lucky ones.
我活下來了
I survived.
外面有人幫忙 對你這樣的人來說
There is help out there for people like you.
它叫 電擊療法
It's called electroshock therapy.
來吧 你真的不相信
Come on. You don't really believe
邁克爾?邁爾斯 實際上還活著
that Michael Myers is actually alive.
邁克爾的作品 不是在哈德頓菲爾德完成的，
Michael's work isn't done in Haddonfield,
很快，很快
and soon, very soon.
他會回來殺人的
He'll come home to kill again.
但這次，我會準備好的
But this time, I'll be ready.
說真的，湯姆 我聽說史密斯的墳墓
Seriously, though, Tom. I hear Smith's Grave's
有藍光 自認
having a blue light on self-admission.
你可能想查一下 線路暢通，
You might want to check into it. The lines are open,
所以給我你最好的機會 電話：1-800-968-7825
so give me your best shot at 1-800-968-7825.
給我們一擊
Give us a hit.
杜安
Duane.
你那軟弱的藉口是什麼 為了今晚的心情，杜安？
What's on your feeble excuse for a mind tonight, Duane?
就像說我聽著 每天晚上看你的節目，巴里
Just like to say that I listen to your show every night, Barry.
我覺得你是最棒的，
I think you're the best,
我不能告訴你 我們有多興奮
and I can't tell you how excited we are
你要去拜訪一下
that you'll be paying a little visit
去我們的小鎮 明晚
to our little town tomorrow night.
你有什麼看法嗎 在這裡，杜安，
So do you have a point to make here, Duane,
或者我應該繼續 打猴子屁股？
or should I just keep spanking the monkey?
巴里，你太過分了
Barry, you're too much.
我只想說 我能理解
I'd just like to say that I understand
事情是怎麼變的 在90年代
how things have changed in the '90s.
軍隊裡的同性戀
Gays in the military.
把你的丈夫都砍掉， 成為民族英雄
Cut off your husbands dojigger, become a national hero.
我只是看不出任何意義
I just can't see any sense
帶來萬聖節 回到哈頓菲爾德
in bringing Halloween back to Haddonfield.
廢物，廢物謝謝你，杜安
Wank, wank. Thank you, Duane.
你現在可以離開我了
You may leave me now.
下一個來電者
Next caller.
我說是時候了
I say it's about time
他們在萬聖節重演 在這個鎮上
they had a Halloween revival in this town.
現在我的孩子們 別再逼我發瘋了
Now my kids can stop driving me crazy.
那個瘋子要麼早就死了 或者已經遠去了
That maniac's either long dead or long gone.
不管怎樣， 我說讓我們埋了那個笨蛋，
Either way, I say let's bury the sucker,
開始派對吧
get the party started.
爪子哇哦，鋤頭：！
Paw. Whoa-hoe:!
啤酒！是啊！
Beer! Yeah!
謝謝您下一個
Thank you. Next.
巴里，發生了什麼事
Barry, what happened
對他的精神科醫生來說， 盧米斯？
to that psychiatrist of his, Loomis?
我聽說老江湖醫生死了
I heard the old quack was dead.
什麼？你是嗎 找推薦人？
What? Are you looking for a referral?
沒有死
Not dead.
只是非常退休
Just very much retired.
我想我們可以 別再打電話了
I think we'll take a little break from the callers.
上帝啊
Good God.
特倫斯，進來！
Terence, come in!
多麼美好的夜晚！
What a night!
甚至不是一個標誌 在那條路上走了五英里
Not even so much as a sign for five miles on that road.
這就是鄉村的美麗
That's the beauty of the countryside.
我靠它茁壯成長
I thrive on it.
上帝啊
God.
-你看起來不錯，山姆 -啊，我感覺好極了
- You look good, Sam. - Ah, I feel great.
我做了手術，整形手術，
I had surgery, plastic surgery,
植皮花了一大筆錢，
skin grafts. It cost a fortune,
但至少我沒有 再嚇唬人了
but at least I don't frighten people anymore.
啊，別告訴我 尊敬的拉斯普京
Ah, don't tell me that the revered Rasputin
史密斯的樹林已經長大了 自滿於年老，
of Smith's Grove has grown complacent in his old age,
我不相信 一會兒
and I won't believe that for a second.
我不記得你了 在家裡打電話，韋恩醫生
Well, I can't remember you making house calls, Dr. Wynn.
尤其是在這個時候
Especially at this hour.
嗯，你說得對
Mm, and you're right.
我是來慶祝的
I've come to celebrate.
你為什麼要聽 對那個混蛋？
Why are you listening to that jerk?
哦這是一個程式 關於哈登菲爾德
Oh. It's a program about Haddonfield.
我在錄
I'm taping it.
[嬰兒啼哭1
[Baby crying 1
所以誰負責
So who is responsible
為了參加萬聖節集會 一起幹什麼？
for getting the Halloween rally thingie together?
我們是 是哈德頓菲爾德初級學院
We are. It's the Haddonfield Junior College.
但為什麼要這麼麻煩 扔這個晚會？
But why go to all the trouble of throwing this soiree?
如果萬聖節 在哈德頓菲爾德被禁止了嗎？
So what if Halloween has been banned in Haddonfield?
-我是說，誰在乎？ -是的！
- I mean, who cares? - We do!
我們住在這裡
We live here.
我們該繼續生活了
It's time we got on with our lives.
明晚就是這樣 就是這樣
That's what tomorrow night is all about.
夥計，這個鎮快死了，巴里
Man, this town is dying, Barry.
真的你知道的，
Wow. You know,
我聽說邁克爾?邁爾斯被指責
I've heard Michael Myers blamed
今晚很多事情， 但這是第一次
for a lot of things tonight, but this is a first.
他真的被殺了 經濟
He's actually killed the economy.
看，明晚 當我們改變一切的時候，
Look, tomorrow night is when we change all that,
尤其是有你 你的直播
especially having you do your broadcast live...
你已經達到 哈德頓菲爾德緊急服務
You have reached Haddonfield Emergency Services.
由於嚴重 天氣狀況，
Due to severe weather conditions,
所有電路 暫時很忙
all circuits are momentarily busy.
如果這不是緊急情況--
If this is not an emergency--
你會爬上去的 和巴爾在舞臺上？
You gonna get up there on the stage with ol' Barr?
-嗯，是的，我會的 -是嗎？
- Uh, yeah, I will. - Yeah?
好， 明天晚上見
Well, I'll see you tomorrow night.
這是“頂嘴” 和巴里?西姆斯在一起
This is "Back Talk" with Barry Simms.
打電話給我 電話：1-800-968-7825
Give me a call at 1-800-968-7825.
那是1-800-你-糟透了
That's 1-800-YOU-SUCK.
所以來吧，你們所有人 鬼怪信徒在那裡
So come on, all you Bogeyman believers out there.
給我打個電話今晚打電話給我
Give me a call. Call me tonight.
32年後，
Well, after 32 years,
猜猜最後是誰 放棄職責
guess who is finally relinquishing his duties
作為首席行政官 史密斯的樹林
as chief administrator of Smith's Grove.
上帝啊 你不是說你是--
Good God. You don't mean to say you're--
退休？我路過 我親自告訴你這個消息
Retiring? I came by to give you the news myself.
好吧，我祝你好運，特倫斯
Well, I wish you well, Terence.
已經在計畫階段了 一段時間了
It's been in the planning stages for some time now.
對老朋友
To old friends...
到退休，
to retirement,
新的開始
to new beginnings.
老朋友
Old friends.
山姆，我要你回來 去史密斯的樹林
Sam, I want you to come back to Smith's Grove.
你應該知道 如果不明智的話
You should know that ifs not wise
在我身上玩萬聖節惡作劇
to play Halloween pranks on me.
這不是惡作劇 你是我選擇的人，山姆
It's no prank. You're the one I've chosen, Sam.
我要你回來
I want you to come back.
六年前中風後，
After my stroke six years ago,
他們實際上 不得不用手槍頂著我的頭
they practically had to hold a pistol to my head
為了讓我退休，
to get me to retire,
但現在情況不同了
but things are different now.
我與眾不同
I'm different.
我把鬼埋了
I've buried the ghosts.
我把它們埋了 在這本手稿裡
I've buried them in this--this manuscript.
我不想練習 再吃藥了
I don't want to practice medicine anymore.
他們來了 別告訴我
They're coming. Don't tell me.
你叫瓊，聖女貞德，
Your name is Joan, Joan of Arc,
你也是 聽到聲音了吧？
and you're also hearing voices, right?
現在，誰來了？
Now, who's coming?
我是邁克爾， 邁爾斯
It's Michael, Michael Myers.
聽著，有人，任何人，幫幫我
Look, someone, anyone, help me.
盧米斯醫生，你在外面嗎？ 你能聽到我說話嗎，魯米斯醫生？
Dr. Loomis, are you out there? Can you hear me, Dr. Loomis?
-我需要你的説明！ -求你了，求你了，不，不
- I need your help! - Please, please, no, no.
拜託，夠了
Please, enough of this.
我勒個去 今晚要去嗎？
What the hell is going on tonight?
這個州的每個瘋子 正在呼叫
Every loony in the state is calling.
這是什麼，滿月？
What is this, a full moon?
夥計，猜猜萬聖節 把所有的怪人都帶出來
Man, guess Halloween brings out all the wackos.
我迫不及待地想等我們 明天去哈頓菲爾德
I can't wait until we gel to Haddonfield tomorrow.
我要把蓋子撕掉 邁爾斯B.S
I'm gonna rip the lid off of this Myers B.S.
現在我瘋了，虛弱的聽眾
Now I'm mad, feeble listeners.
現在我瘋了
Now I'm mad.
噓
Shh.
沒關係
It's okay.
你真可愛
You're so cute.
噓
Shh.
是的
Yes.
沒關係
It's okay.
你真可愛對
You're so cute. Yes.
我喘息著]
I gasps]
不！
No!
離我們遠點！
Leave us alone!
我喘息著]
I gasps]
你不能生孩子， 邁克爾
You can't have the baby, Michael.
〔9394151〕 你不能生孩子
[9394151 You can't have the baby.
夠了
Enough...
邁克爾?邁爾斯
of this Michael Myers...
瞎扯！
bullshit!
你們這些愚蠢的孩子 大約三秒鐘
You stupid kids got about three seconds to get
離我的財產遠點！
the hell off my property!
1, 2...
是傑米?勞埃德
ltwas Jamie Lloyd.
那是六年前的事了，山姆
That was six years ago, Sam.
你知道她和他一起死了 在爆炸中你知道的
You know she died with him in that explosion. You know it.
有人就是這樣 希望我們相信，
That's what someone would like us to believe,
但我告訴你， 邁克爾還活著我--
but I tell you, Michael is alive. I--
我能感覺到他那邪惡的心臟在跳動
I can feel his evil heart beating.
我能看到他就像我看到的一樣 那些年前
I can see him just as I did all those years ago
在這些牆後面，
behind these very same walls,
盯著，盯著，
staring, staring,
總是越來越強壯
always growing stronger.
拜託，作為我的同事，
Please, as my colleague,
作為我的朋友，
as my friend,
我不能再這樣了
I can't go through this again.
不是一個人
Not alone.
我需要你的説明來阻止他
I need your help to stop him.
永利博士我——我沒想到你會進來 今天早上
Dr. Wynn. I--I didn't expect you in this morning.
道恩，呃，我是盧米斯醫生，
Dawn, uh, this is Dr. Loomis,
我告訴你的那個人
the man I was telling you about.
哦，是的很高興見到你 去見你，醫生
Oh, yes. It's a pleasure to meet you, Doctor.
有你會很高興的 回到醫院
It will be wonderful to have you back at the hospital.
韋恩醫生，有件事 你應該知道
Dr. Wynn, there's something you should know.
道恩，我想讓你 魯米斯醫生他需要什麼，
Dawn, I'd like you to get Dr. Loomis anything he needs,
檔、測試、記錄 我們所經歷的每一次治療
files, tests, records of every treatment we've ever
給前病人服用 我們的，邁克爾?邁爾斯
administered to a former patient of ours, Michael Myers.
邁克爾?邁爾斯？
Michael Myers?
出什麼事了嗎？
Is something wrong?
我剛接到一個電話
I just received a phone call.
那個女孩，傑米?勞埃德， 她的屍體被發現了
That girl, Jamie Lloyd, her body was found
今天早上在哈德頓菲爾德附近
this morning near Haddonfield.
通知哈德頓菲爾德警長 告訴他我們在路上
Notify the Haddonfield sheriff. Tell him we're on the way.
我要全體員工保持警惕
I want the entire staff on alert.
我們進入紅色警戒區 24小時
We go to code-red lockdown for 24 hours.
如果那個瘋子真的在外面，
If that maniac is really out there,
我打算讓他活著回來
I plan to bring him back alive.
喲，G，怎麼了？
Yo, G, what's up?
巴里是我芝加哥的老家男孩
Barry's my homeboy from Chicago.
是的，那個巴里?西姆斯
Yes, that Barry Simms.
貝絲和我在這場演唱會上不開心
Beth and I are down on this gig.
丹尼
Danny.
聽著，你今晚帶著小隊來，
Look, you just bring the posse tonight,
我們會幫你接電話的
and we'll hook you up.
和平！
Peace!
丹尼看起來不可愛嗎 打扮成他叔叔蒂姆？
Doesn't Danny look cute dressed up as his Uncle Tim?
偉大的現在我有一個六歲的孩子 一個兒子的幫派成員
Great. Now I've got a six-year-old gang member for a son.
很完美
Perfect.
這就是著名的 蒂姆大步跨過胃部捶打器
This is the famous Tim Strode stomach pounder.
你接受挑戰了嗎？
You down for the challenge?
打我，G
Hit me, G.
幹得好，丹
Good try, Dan man'
你最好還是喝橙汁
You better stick to orange juice.
該死的損壞我的財產
Shitheads. Defacing my property.
嘿給他們看
Heh. Showed them'
約翰，他們只是孩子
John, they were just kids.
孩子們，親愛的黛布拉， 是什麼毀了這個國家
Kids, my dear Debra, are what's ruining this country.
無論你走到哪裡， 是一樣的東西
Everywhere you go, it's the same damn thing.
他媽的沒有尊重
There's no goddamn respect.
我把箱子放下
I rest my case.
卡拉，你不會通過考試的 空著肚子
Kara, you'll never pass that exam on an empty stomach.
“認知療法，” “情緒障礙”
"Cognitive therapy," "emotional disorders.“
他們在教你什麼 現在在大學裡，
What are they teaching you in college these days,
你瘋了嗎？
the an of going crazy?
這叫心理學，媽媽
It's called psychology, Mom.
住在這房子裡就夠了 把任何人逼瘋
Living in this house is enough to drive anyone crazy.
哦，是嗎？ 是誰問你的
Oh, yeah? Well, who the hell asked you
回來這裡 首先呢？
to come back here in the first place?
最好帶丹尼去學校
Better get Danny to school.
她沒露面 她自己一家五年了
Doesn't show her face around her own family for five years.
然後回來期待我們 鋪開紅地毯
Then comes back and expects us to roll out the red carpet.
你覺得上大學
You think going to college
會彌補的 為了你的錯誤，女孩？嗯？
is gonna make up for your mistakes, girl? Huh?
-拜託 -別理她，爸爸
- Please. - Lay off her, Dad.
我們走吧，丹尼
Let's go, Danny.
卡拉，等等拜託，約翰
Kara, wait. Please, John.
我們就不能坐一次嗎 想成為一家人嗎？
Can't we just sit down for once and try to be a family?
沒事的，媽媽
It's all right, Mom.
哦，就這樣，黛布拉 是的，繼續給她現金
Oh, that's it, Debra. Yeah, just keep slipping her the cash.
你知道，當你在做的時候， 我有個好主意
You know, while you're at it, I got a great idea.
在這裡在這裡你為什麼不給她 我們所有的錢？
Here. Here. Why don't you give her all of our goddamn money?
你為什麼不讓她一個人呆著？
Why don't you leave her alone?
什麼都沒變，是嗎？
Nothing ever changes, does it?
你什麼時候醒來？
When are you gonna wake up?
我有消息告訴你，女孩
I got news for you, girl.
在你回來之前， 一切都很順利
Before you came around, everything was going fine
直到你降落在我們家門口
till you landed on our doorstep...
你和那個小
you and that little...
你這個混蛋
bastard of yours.
我只看到一個混蛋 在這房子裡
I see only one bastard in this house.
丹尼
Danny.
離她遠點！
Get away from her!
你閉嘴， 別插手！
You shut up, and stay out of this!
-為他殺人 -約翰，請不要
- Kill for him. - John, please don't.
你再也不能那樣跟我說話了
You ever talk to me like that again.
上帝保佑我
And so help me God...
你明白嗎？
You understand?
把刀給我，丹尼
Give me the knife, Danny.
嘿！
Hey!
嘿！讓路 為了哈丁縣的快車！
Hey! Make way for the Hardin County Express!
蒂姆在哪裡？我們應該 看一下今晚的活動清單
Where's Tim? We're supposed to go over the list of events for tonight.
哦，天哪他這樣對你？
Oh, God. He do that to you?
另一集 “父親最清楚”
Another episode of "Father Knows Best“
在斯特羅德家
at the Strode house.
這次到底發生了什麼？
What the hell happened this time?
我喘息著]
I gasps]
你怎麼了？
What's gotten into you?
很高興見到你，僅此而已 你們還好吧？
Just glad to see you, that's all. You guys okay?
今晚是我們帶來的夜晚 一些生活回到這個城市
Tonight's the night we bring some life back into this town.
媽的，貝絲，我們為什麼 必須是那個
Shit, Beth, why do we have to be the ones
組織這個該死的集市？
to organize this friggin' fair?
我是說，現在只是萬聖節
I mean, it's only Halloween.
多少次 我必須告訴你嗎？
How many times do I have to tell you?
丹尼，你認識爺爺 不是真的傷害我，對吧？
Now, Danny, you know Grandpa didn't really hurt me, right?
好的，媽媽
Right, Mom.
好吧，你最好去趕公共汽車
Well, you better go catch your bus.
但是今晚你回家的時候，
But tonight when you come home,
我們不給糖就搗蛋，好嗎？
we'll go trick-or-treating, okay?
好的-
Okay-
我愛你，丹尼
I love you, Danny.
愛你，媽媽
Love you, Mommy.
給我擠一下
Give me a squeeze.
嗯
Mm.
是啊可以
Yeah. Okay.
只是活不下去 和她在一起，黛布拉
Just can't live with her anymore, Debra'
你不明白，是嗎？
You don't understand, do you?
不是卡拉的事
It's not about Kara'
是關於你的
It's about you.
我不在乎她做了什麼
I don't care what she's done.
她是你女兒
She's your daughter.
她不再是我女兒了
She's not my daughter anymore.
貝絲，那個活著的人是誰 在你對面的大廳？
Beth, who's that guy who lives across the hall from you?
為什麼？你有興趣嗎？
Why? You interested?
是的，對
Yeah, right.
他總是盯著 從他的窗戶出去
He's always staring out his window.
昨晚， 我發現他在看我
Last night, I caught him watching me.
那一定是湯米
That must be Tommy.
從1到10的怪異程度來看， 他得了13分左右
On a weirdness scale of 1 to 10, he rates about a 13.
據說，一些可怕的東西
Supposedly, some scary shit
發生在他身上 他小時候，
happened to him when he was a kid,
把他的頭弄得一團糟
messed up his head pretty bad.
不過，他是無害的 可能只是寂寞
He's harmless, though. Probably just lonely.
或者是角質 好久沒感覺了
Or horny, something you probably haven't felt in a while.
提姆
Tim...
萬聖節快樂！ 布蘭肯希普夫人！
Happy Halloween. Mrs. Blankenship!
生活中最美好的部分 在那個寄宿處
Best part about living in that boardinghouse
那個瘋婆婆
is that crazy old lady
聽不到卡車的聲音 開車穿過她的客廳
wouldn't hear a truck drive through her living room.
拜託，聽著， 你得聽我說
Please, look, you've gotta listen to me.
他們來了他們來了
They're coming. They're coming.
隱瑪律可夫模型 是的，所以他們來了
Hmm. Yeah, so they're coming.
他們來了別告訴我
They're coming. Don't tell me.
你叫瓊，聖女貞德，
Your name is Joan, Joan of Arc,
你也能聽到聲音， 正確的？
and you're also hearing voices, right?
快點，現在 誰來了？
Come on, now. Who's coming?
我是邁克爾， 邁爾斯
It's Michael, Michael Myers.
聽著，有人，誰來幫我
Look, someone, anyone help me.
盧米斯醫生，你在外面嗎？ 你能聽到我說話嗎，博士--
Dr. Loomis, are you out there? Can you hear me, Dr.--
我是邁克爾，邁克爾?邁爾斯
It's Michael, Michael Myers.
…請注意？ 611路公車
...attention, please? Bus 611
-從皮蒂亞克，拉塞爾維爾 -聽著，有人，誰來幫我
- from Pontiac, Russellville... - Look, someone, anyone help me.
盧米斯醫生，你在外面嗎？ 你能聽到我說話嗎，魯米斯醫生？
Dr. Loomis, are you out there? Can you hear me, Dr. Loomis?
-……耽擱了一個小時 -盧米斯醫生，我需要你的説明
- ...delayed one hour. - Dr. Loomis, I need your help.
上帝，請幫助我
God, please help.
可以給我嗎 請注意？
May I have your attention, please?
從皮奧里亞來的34路公共汽車， 拉塞爾維爾和加德納，
Bus 34 from Peoria, Russellville, and Gardner,
全程服務 伊利諾州芝加哥，
with through service for Chicago, Illinois,
五分鐘後到
will be arriving in five minutes.
有票乘客， 請在門裡面等
Ticketed passengers, please wait inside the door
直到344路公共汽車到達
until arrival of bus number 344
先生，我能為您效勞嗎？
Can I help you, sir?
你能告訴我公共汽車是否到了嗎 昨晚從皮蒂亞克來的？
Can you tell me if a bus arrived from Pontiac last night?
當然有
Sure did.
你在找人嗎？
Are you looking for someone?
謝謝您
Thank you.
可以給我嗎 請注意？
May I have your attention, please?
34路公共汽車， 去芝加哥的航班已經到了
Bus number 34, service to Chicago, has arrived
現在可以登機了 通過側門
and is now ready for boarding through the side door.
[嬰兒啼哭1
[Baby crying 1
上帝啊
Jesus.
噓
Shh.
不，噓沒關係
No. Shh. It's okay.
沒關係沒關係
It's okay. It's okay.
沒關係，夥計
It's okay, man'
沒關係
It's okay.
噓！
Shh!
上帝啊那是什麼？
Good God. What's that?
這是他的標誌
It's his mark.
他要回家了
He's coming home.
親愛的上帝
Dear God.
傑米
Jamie.
現在只有上帝能幫助她，先生
Only God can help her now, sir.
山姆，不要 讓他們來照顧她
Sam, don't. Let them take care of her.
-盧米斯醫生 -是嗎？
- Dr. Loomis. - Yes?
他們告訴我你會來的
They told me you'd be coming.
現在我建議你右轉 回到你的精神病院
Now I'd suggest you go right on back to your crackpot asylum.
你們這些人 我鎮上沒有生意
You people got no business in my town.
邁克爾?邁爾斯是我的事
Michael Myers is my business.
這裡已經安靜了六年了，
It's been quiet here for six years,
這就是它會留下來的方式，
and that's the way it's gonna stay,
我現在最不需要的就是
and the last thing I need now
你是在四處轉悠嗎 滔滔不絕地講鬼故事
is you going around spouting off ghost stories.
我想是個鬼魂 就這樣，嗯？
I suppose it was a ghost that did all this, eh?
是個鬼魂在說話 昨晚在廣播裡，
It was a ghost talking on the radio last night,
那是個鬼魂 現在就在這裡？
and that's a ghost being carried out here right now?
喲，看看
Yo, check it out.
今晚會是個殺手
Tonight's gonna be killer.
卡拉，我發誓， 總有一天，
Kara, I swear, one of these days,
你會迷路的 在那件事上
you're gonna get lost in that thing.
我找不到我的學期論文
I can't find my term paper.
抄別人的就行了
Just copy someone else's.
我總是這樣做 原汁原味
I do it all the time. Works primo.
哦，媽的
Oh, shit.
看來你的孩子 他自己很有想像力
Looks like your little boy's got himself quite an imagination.
他一直 做噩夢
He's been having nightmares.
我覺得很酷
I think it's cool.
一定是噩夢
Must be some nightmares.
貝絲，我們還有工作要做！
Beth, we got work to do!
嘿，你沒事吧？
Hey, are you gonna be okay?
別擔心
Don't worry.
我親愛的咕咕聲]
I baby coos]
我需要看醫生
I need to see a doctor.
怎麼了？
What seems to be the problem?
呃，是我的孩子是的--
Uh, it's my baby. It's--
出了事故
There's been an accident.
什麼事故？
What kind of accident?
給我找個醫生！
Get me a doctor now!
安全
Security.
山姆，什麼都沒有 你現在可以幫她了
Sam, there's nothing you can do for her now.
哦
Oh.
啊我馬上回來
Ah. I'll be right back.
UL織布機？
UL Looms?
是啊
Yeah.
盧米斯醫生， 謝天謝地你來了
Dr. Loomis, thank God you're here.
你昨晚聽到她了， 你不是嗎？
You heard her last night, didn't you?
是傑米
It was Jamie.
我很抱歉我--
I'm sorry. I--
我不認識你，是嗎？我--
I don't know you, do I? I--
我是湯米，湯米?道爾
I'm Tommy, Tommy Doyle.
勞麗?斯特羅德，傑米的母親，
Laurie Strode, Jamie's mother,
在照顧我 當
was babysitting me the night when...
湯米?道爾
Tommy Doyle.
你在這裡幹什麼？
What are you doing here?
拜託， 我需要知道真相
Please, I need to know the truth.
梅爾斯 他已經回家了，不是嗎？
Michael Myers has come home, hasn't he?
你知道什麼 關於邁克爾？
W-What do you know about Michael'?
我知道他還在外面
I know he's still out there.
鎮上的人， 他們想讓我們相信他死了，
People in this town, they want us to believe he's dead,
但我知道我一直都知道
but I know. I've always known.
她在外面 為她的生命而戰
She's out there and fighting for her life.
如果她死了，
If she should die,
她是他最後一個血統
she is the last of his bloodline.
不，盧米斯醫生， 她不是最後一個
No, Dr. Loomis, she's not the last.
哦，天哪，有一家人，
Oh, God, there's a family,
人民的親屬 是誰收養了勞麗
relatives of the people who adopted Laurie, the Strodes.
他們住在邁爾斯家
They're living in the Myers' house.
盧米斯醫生， 關於邁克爾，只是
Dr. Loomis, about Michael, it's just
-我的理論，但是-- -就是他
- a theory of mine, but-- - That's him.
呃，今晚見我， 9：在校園集會上
Uh, meet me tonight, 9:00 at the campus rally.
湯米，等等！等待！
Tommy, wait! Wait!
[嬰兒啼哭1
[Baby crying 1
湯米，等等！
Tommy, wait!
哦，給你
Oh, there you are.
那個男孩是誰？
Who is that boy?
一個老朋友
An old friend.
嗯
Mm.
偉大的
Great.
“93美元P$I -我很抱歉，
"I 93$P$ I - I'm very sorry,
斯特羅德太太，但是
Mrs. Strode, but...
一切都好嗎？
is everything all right?
你是誰？
Who are you?
我來幫助你的家人
I came to help your family.
[嬰兒啼哭1
[Baby crying 1
噓
Shh.
噓沒關係
Shh. it's okay.
好吧，史蒂文
Okay, Steven.
你喜歡這個名字嗎？
You like that name?
是的，我覺得很適合你
Yeah, I think it suits you.
[史蒂文哭我
[Steven crying I
沒關係
It's okay.
我不會讓你出事的
I won't let anything happen to you.
15年來，我一直沉迷於
For 15 years, I've been obsessed
找出 他內心到底發生了什麼
to find out what was going on inside of him.
這是我一生的工作
It's been my life work
以及我最終的失敗
and my ultimate failure.
這個力量，這個東西 住在他體內的
This force, this thing that lived inside of him
來源太暴力了， 對你來說太致命了
came from a source too violent, too deadly for you to imagine.
它——它在他體內生長
It--it grew inside him...
污染了他的靈魂
contaminating his soul.
那純粹是邪惡
It was pure evil.
你怎麼想的 他會回來嗎？
What makes you think he'll come back here?
這房子對他來說是神聖的
This house is sacred to him'
他所有的記憶都在這裡， 他的憤怒！
He has all his memories here, his rage!
斯特羅德太太，我求你了，
Mrs. Strode, I beg of you,
別讓你的家人 遭受同樣的命運
don't let your family suffer the same fate
那個勞麗 她的女兒也很痛苦
that Laurie and her daughter suffered.
傑米？我——我以為--
Jamie? I--I thought that--
她被找到了 在哈德東菲爾德外面被刺傷
She's been found outside Haddonfield stabbed.
我該怎麼辦？
What should I do?
我都寫下來了，
I've written it all down for you,
但你一刻也不能失去
but you haven't a moment to lose.
斯特羅德夫人，
Mrs. Strode,
邁爾斯回來了 去哈德東菲爾德殺人
Michael Myers has come back to Haddonfield to kill.
斯特羅德房地產
Strode Real Estate.
約翰，可怕的事 已經發生了
John, something terrible has happened.
你現在想要什麼，黛布拉？
What do you want now, Debra?
一個男人經過房子，
A man came by the house,
精神病醫生 我叫盧米斯，
a psychiatrist by the name of Loomis,
他告訴我 關於可怕的事情
and he told me about the terrible things
發生在我們家的事
that happened here in our house.
黛布拉，你到底是什麼 和陌生人聊天，
Debra, what the hell are you doing talking to strangers,
-讓他進我們家？ -約翰，
- letting him into our house? - John,
他們找到了傑米?勞埃德 今天早上
they found Jamie Lloyd this morning.
有人想殺了她
Someone tried to kill her.
黛布拉，我不知道什麼 你到底在說什麼
Debra, I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
我——你應該停止看 那些該死的電視談話節目！
I--You ought to stop watching those damn TV talk shows!
我得到了 孩子們離開這裡，
I'm getting the children out of here,
至少在我知道之前 發生什麼事
at least until I know what's going on.
約翰，我要你 和我們一起去
John, I want you to come with us.
是啊
Yeah.
你知道，黛布拉 你現在丟了
You know, Debra' you've lost it now.
你知道嗎，黛布拉？ 你剛剛把它弄丟了
You know that, Debra? You've just lost it.
你感動我們的原因 進了這房子，
The reason you moved us into this house,
你哥哥永遠也賣不出去
your brother could never sell it
因為這裡發生的事， 他能嗎？
because of what happened here, could he?
你知道，
And you knew,
你沒告訴我們，約翰
and you didn't tell us, John.
你知道的
You knew.
該死的
God damn it.
萬聖節快樂，小女孩
Happy Halloween, little girl.
你好
Hello.
我們想要孩子
We want the child.
這是誰？
Who is this?
邁克爾
Michael.
我-我來了
I-I'm coming.
是的，我來了
Yes, I'm coming.
準備好了嗎？哦，是的！
You ready? Oh, yes!
對！對！
Yes! Yes!
對是的，我來了， 好吧，
Yes. Yeah, I'm coming, all right,
你最好在那裡， 萬聖節收穫集市
and you better be there, the Halloween Harvest Fair.
我們一起做吧
Let's do it together.
對不起的
Sorry.
媽媽？我回家了！
Mom? I'm home!
你好？
Hello?
媽媽？
Mom?
丹尼？
Danny?
媽媽？
Mom?
你在嗎？
Are you there?
你在這裡幹什麼？
What are you doing here?
[史蒂文哭我
[Steven crying I
我是你的鄰居 在街對面
I'm your neighbor from across the street.
我是湯米?道爾
I'm Tommy Doyle.
你在和我兒子做什麼
What are you doing with my son.
我媽媽呢？
And where's my mother?
呃，她不在這裡
Uh, she wasn't here
丹尼回家的時候--
when Danny came home from--
丹尼，下樓去
Danny, go downstairs.
但湯米是我的新朋友， 他對恐龍瞭若指掌
But Tommy's my new friend, and he knows all about dinosaurs.
你有危險跟我來
You're in danger. Come with me.
嗨，B太太
Hi, Mrs. B.
[史蒂文哭我
[Steven crying I
呃，你真的不指望我們 留在這裡，是嗎？
Uh, you don't really expect us to stay here, do you?
想讓你照看你的房子
Want you to watch your house.
你可以看到一切 從那個視窗
You can see everything from that window.
你知道這有多瘋狂嗎？
Do you know how insane this is?
我應該是誰 要找嗎？
Who am I supposed to be looking for?
他
Him.
是的，沒關係
Yeah, it's okay.
沒事的，史蒂文
It's okay, Steven.
媽媽
Mommy.
媽媽！
Mom!
現在不行，丹尼
Not now, Danny.
[史蒂文哭我
[Steven crying I
幹得好
Here you go.
什麼？嘿
What? Hey.
來吧，夥計
Come on, man.
來，讓我試試
Here, let me give it a try.
在那裡
There.
看到了嗎？
See?
所需要的一切 是母親的撫摸
All it takes is a mother's touch.
邁克爾叔叔， 請不要傷害我
Uncle Michael, please don't hurt me.
哦，上帝，請原諒我！
Oh, God, please forgive me!
你的工作現在完成了，傑米
Your work is done now, Jamie.
我又讓你失望了傑米
I let you down again. Jamie.
我不該離開你
I never should have left you.
符文是 一種早期的字母表
Runes are a kind of early alphabet
起源於北方 歐洲約西元前500年
that originated in Northern Europe about 500 B.C.
它們是雕刻的符號 用石頭或木頭，
They were symbols carved out of stone or pieces of wood,
在異教儀式中用來預示 未來的事件和召喚魔法
used in pagan rituals to portend future events and invoke magic.
從所有的符文中，
From all the runes,
索恩有 最消極的影響
Thorn had the most negative influence.
在古代德魯伊中，
Among the ancient Druids,
荊棘代表惡魔 傳播疾病，
Thorn represented a demon that spread sickness,
毀壞的莊稼，
destroyed crops,
使數百人死亡 成千上萬的人
brought death to hundreds of thousands of people.
根據凱爾特人的傳說， 每個部落一個孩子
According to Celtic legend, one child from each tribe
被選來施暴 帶著荊棘的詛咒
was chosen to be inflicted with the curse of Thorn
獻血 他的近親
to offer the blood sacrifices of its next of kin
-在Samhain的夜晚 -萬聖節
- on the night of Samhain. - Halloween.
一家人的犧牲
The sacrifice of one family
意味著拯救生命 整個部落的人
meant sparing the lives of an entire tribe.
那你為什麼 如此關心我們
So why are you so concerned about us
如果邁克爾只在外面 殺了他的家人？
if Michael's only out to kill his family?
在他心目中，任何活著的人 他家裡有他的家人
In his mind, anyone living in his house is his family.
多年來，我一直堅信 一定有原因，
For years, I've been convinced there must be some reason,
一些方法 在邁克爾斯瘋狂的背後，
some method behind MichaeFs madness,
以及共同的聯繫 我發現是刺
and the common link I found is Thorn.
德魯伊也很棒 數學家和天文學家
The druids were also great mathematicians and astronomers.
荊棘符號實際上是 星群
The Thorn symbol is actually a constellation of stars
不時出現的 萬聖節之夜
that appears from time to time on Halloween night.
無論何時出現，他都會出現
Whenever it appears, he appears.
我追溯到1963年，
I've traced it back to 1963,
當邁克爾謀殺的時候 他的妹妹裘蒂絲
when Michael murdered his sister Judith.
下一次是在1978年
Then the next time was in 1978.
邁克爾逃走了 來自史密斯森林
Michael escapes from Smith's Grove.
十年後，
It happened a decade later,
在那之後的一年， 他又殺人了
and the year after that, he kills again.
現在傑米說邁克爾回來了，
Now Jamie says Michael is back,
六年來第一次， 荊棘再次出現
and for the first time in six years, Thorn reappears.
巧合？
Coincidence?
會發生什麼 如果他成功了，
What would happen if he succeeded,
如果他殺了最後一個成員 他的家人？
if he killed the last member of his family?
然後邁克爾的權力就會終結，
Then Michael's power would end,
咒語就會傳下去 給另一個孩子
and the curse would be passed on to another child.
我想這就是為什麼這些人，
I think that's why these people,
不管他們是誰， 是為了傑米的孩子
whoever they are, are after Jamie's baby...
使他 邁克爾的最後犧牲
to make him Michael's final sacrifice.
你要去哪裡？
Where are you going?
找到唯一能 在太遲之前阻止他
To find the only man who can stop him before it's too late.
哦，不丹尼在哪裡？
Oh, no. Where's Danny?
丹尼？！丹尼？！
Danny?! Danny?!
布蘭肯希普夫人， 你見過嗎--
Mrs. Blankenship, have you seen--
丹尼，不要走開
Danny, don't ever walk off
不告訴我 你要去哪裡
without telling me where you're going.
帶他上樓
Take him upstairs.
鎖上門， 等我回來
Lock the door, and wait til I get back.
卡拉，不管你做什麼
Kara, whatever you do...
不要回你家
don't go back to your house.
你讓她知道了！
You let it get to her!
你怎麼能？
How could you?
盧米斯醫生，手術期間，
Dr. Loomis, during surgery,
我們發現傑米 子宮在出血，
we discovered that Jamie's uterus was hemorrhaging,
我們找到了這個
and we found this.
它是胎盤液
It's placental fluid.
天堂裡的上帝， 你是說
Good God in Heaven, do you mean to say that...
我估計她是生的 不超過24小時前
I estimate she gave birth no more than 24 hours ago.
問題是， 孩子在哪裡？
And the question is, where is the baby?
我想我——我可能已經知道了
I think I--I may already know.
你知道嗎 為什麼我們要慶祝萬聖節？
Do you know why we celebrate Halloween?
因為我們走的時候 不給糖就搗蛋
Because that's when we go trick-or-treating and get candy.
哦，是的，
Oh, well, yes,
但是很久很久以前，
but a long, longtime ago,
那是一個充滿力量的夜晚，
it was a night of great power,
當日子越來越短
when the days grew short
死者的靈魂 回到他們的家
and the spirits of the dead returned to their homes
溫暖自己 在爐邊
to warm themselves by the fireside.
整個土地， 巨大的篝火被點燃
All across the land, huge bonfires were lit.
哦，是的 精彩的慶典；
Oh, there was a marvelous celebration'
人們跳舞， 他們玩遊戲，
People danced, and they played games,
他們穿著盛裝，
and they dressed up in costumes,
希望能驅除邪靈，
hoping to ward off the evil spirits,
尤其是那個妖怪
especially the Bogeyman.
什麼是妖怪？
What's the Bogeyman?
來吧，丹尼
Come on, Danny.
說晚安 布蘭肯希普太太
Say good night to Mrs. Blankenship.
晚安，布蘭肯希普太太
Good night, Mrs. Blankenship.
他聽到了聲音，你知道，
He hears the voice, you know,
就像另一個男孩 住在那房子裡；
just like the other boy that lived in that house'
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
我在照顧他 那天晚上，
I was babysitting with him that night,
小米奇?邁爾斯 住在街對面，
little Mikey Myers that lived across the street,
當聲音響起時，
and that's when the voice came,
他謀殺他妹妹的那晚
the night he murdered his sister.
邁克爾聽到聲音了嗎？
Michael heard a voice?
它告訴他要殺了他的家人
It told him to kill his family.
巴里到底在哪？ 我們走吧！
Now where the hell's Barry? Let's go!
別讓人大吃一驚 提姆，現在就交給我
Don't get starstruck on me now, Tim.
我們有一個真正的議程，
We got a real agenda here,
巴里會幫我們的 把資訊傳出去
and Barry is gonna help us get the message out.
嘿，看
Hey, look.
哈頓菲爾德，你好！
Hello, Haddonfield!
巴里！
Barry!
WKNB推出“回話” 有了巴里?西姆斯，
WKNB presents "Back Talk" with Barry Simms,
住在伊利諾州的哈頓菲爾德
live from Haddonfield, Illinois...
-巴里！ -邁爾斯的家
- Barry! - the home of Michael Myers.
黛布拉！我回家了！
Debra! I'm home!
謝謝你的晚餐
Thanks for the dinner.
出來，出來， 無論你在哪裡
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
該死的
God damn it.
她真的走了
She actually left.
倒楣
Shit.
我知道發生了什麼；
I know what's going on'
一定是那個妖怪
It must be the Bogeyman.
哈！我來了，妖怪
Ha! Here I come, Bogeyman.
&因為，你知道， 我真的很害怕
'Cause, you know, I am really scared.
我勒個去？
What the hell?
電源關閉
Power's off.
告訴我，孩子們，感覺如何 終於過萬聖節了
Tell me, kids, hows it feel to finally pull Halloween
不言而喻 哈德頓菲爾德衣櫃？
out of the proverbial Haddonfield closet?
我們在這裡要說的 我們將不再
What we're saying here is we will no longer
讓那些力量 控制我們的思想
let the powers that be control our minds.
多年來， 萬聖節代表著
For years, Halloween has represented
一切都是錯的 有了哈德頓菲爾德，
everything that's wrong with Haddonfield,
但邁克爾?邁爾斯早已離去
but Michael Myers is long gone.
世上沒有妖怪
There is no Bogeyman.
哇哦；
Whoa'
她會生氣嗎 在袋子裡，蒂姆？
Does she get this riled up in the sack, Tim?
我打賭她穿著 無襠內褲
I bet she wears crotchless panties
像狗一樣叫
and barks like a dog.
貝絲，你說什麼，
Beth, what do you say,
親愛的，你和我，呃
honey, you and me, uh...
正如我所說，我們已經 因為害怕而停止行動
As I was saying, we have to stop acting out of fear.
看看蒂姆的家人
Just look at Tim's family.
他們住在邁爾斯家
They live in the Myers house.
-你知道嗎？ -是嗎？
- You do? - We do?
嗯，是的，我們有
Uh, yeah, we do.
好房子
Great house.
-嗯 -結實的木頭
- Hmm. - Strong wood.
我懂了你是想告訴我 你真的住在這房子裡
I see. You mean to tell me you actually live in the house
最殘忍的 歷史上的大屠殺？
of the most brutal mass murderer in history?
哇哦！
Whoa!
這是巴里?西姆斯的節目，
This is the Barry Simms show,
當我們回來的時候， 我們將現場向您展示
and when we return, we'll be coming at you live
從那個開始， 唯一的邁爾斯家
from the one, the only Myers house.
怎麼樣 萬聖節的驚喜，孩子們？
Hows that for a Halloween shock, kids?
-跟…頂嘴 -孩子，到你家有多遠？
- "Back Talk“ with... - How far to your house, kid?
大約半英里， 但我不知道
About half a mile, but I don't know
-如果我的家人-- -很好
- if my folks are-- - Good.
-我五分鐘後在那兒等你 -孩子們呢？
- I'll meet you there in five. - What about the kids?
我們應該 扔掉所有的糖果
We're supposed to throw all the candy.
電話！放鬆你的裂縫， 親愛的
Phone! Relax your crack, sweetheart
快嘟嘟 在老房子周圍，
Quick tootle around the old household,
我們就在後面
and we'll be right on back.
把車拉回來
Pull the van out back
好讓我溜出去 這裡很安靜
so that I can sneak out of here nice and quiet.
哦，不不，不，真的 真的，你對我太好了，真的
Oh, no. No, no, really. Really, you're too good to me, really.
不，謝謝你讓我 在中間
No, thanks for putting me in the middle
他媽的很賤 鄉村鄉巴佬裝束，保羅
of this cheap-shit country bumpkin outfit, Paul.
我真的很感激
I really appreciate it.
我的粉絲們期望比這更好
My fans expect better than this.
不，不，聽著，你說
No, no, look, you tell
那個吝嗇的抱怨者 邁克?薩杜奇
that penny-pinching whiner Mike Sarducci
當我回來的時候， 我個人
that when I get back, I am personally
把他的蛋蛋切掉 戴上耳環
gonna cut off his balls and wear 'em as earrings.
該死的貨車在哪？！上帝啊
Where's the goddamn van?! God.
哦，不，我正快跑出去 一個芝士漢堡
Oh, no, I'm trotting out for a cheeseburger.
我要去看演出 去真正的邁爾斯家，
I'm taking the show to the real Myers house,
我們應該在哪裡做的 首先
where we should have done it in the first place.
在那房子裡呆10分鐘，
10 minutes in that house,
我要每種水果蛋糕 在鄉下
and I'll have every fruitcake medium in the country
打電話來， 試圖引導靈魂
calling in, trying to channel the spirit
關於那個女人， 邁爾斯
of that pussy, Michael Myers.
當然，我們可以 關於他的另一個節目；
Sure, we can do another show on him'
踢觀眾 從表面上看，
Kick the audience in the face enough,
他們會-- 他們會把你舔得遍體鱗傷！
and they'll-- they'll lick you all over!
我回來後給你打電話， 保羅再見
I'll call you when I get back, Paul. Bye-bye.
他媽的
Where the fuck...
燈怎麼了？
What happened to the lights?
你真的認為 巴里會出現嗎？
You really think Barry's gonna show up?
但願不會
Let's hope not.
對不起，他原來是 真是個混蛋
Sorry he turned out to be such an asshole.
沒關係
It's okay.
大家都在哪裡？
Where is everyone?
媽媽？卡拉？
Mom? Kara?
他們可能在集市上，
They're probably at the fair,
這就是我們應該去的地方
which is where we should be.
貝絲，嗯，你剛才說的
Beth, um, what you said before
關於邁克爾?邁爾斯 住在我們家裡，
about Michael Myers living in our house,
是真的嗎？
is that really true?
那是一個寒冷的萬聖節夜晚
It was a cold Halloween night.
他站在暗處 透過窗戶看
He stood in the shadows watching through the windows
作為他的妹妹 她男朋友做愛了
as his sister and her boyfriend made love.
然後他悄悄地走了進去，
Then he crept inside,
拿起一把巨大的屠刀，
picked up a huge butcher knife,
就這樣走了 上樓梯
and made his way up these stairs.
他舉起刀 在她身後
He raised the knife up behind her.
她轉過身來，
She turned around,
他捅了她！
and he stabbed her!
別說了，貝絲！
Cut it out, Beth!
我真的不知道
I really didn't know
邁克爾?邁爾斯 住在我家裡，好嗎？
that Michael Myers lived in my house, okay?
把我嚇壞了
Freaks me out.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我只是在胡鬧
I was just fooling around.
沒關係
It's okay.
我們去拿蠟燭吧
Let's get the candles.
請稍等
Just a minute.
“媽媽，下雨了”
♪ Mommy, it's raining ♪
◎天在下紅色的雨◎
♪ it's raining red ♪
“媽媽，下雨了”
♪ Mommy, it's raining ♪
◎天在下紅色的雨◎
♪ it's raining red ♪
“媽媽，下雨了”
♪ Mommy, it's raining ♪
◎天在下紅色的雨◎
♪ it's raining red ♪
◎媽媽，天在下紅色的雨◎
♪ Mommy, it's raining red ♪
“媽媽，下雨了”
♪ Mommy, it's raining ♪
◎天在下紅色的雨◎
♪ it's raining red ♪
“媽媽，下雨了”
♪ Mommy, it's raining ♪
◎天在下紅色的雨◎
♪ it's raining red ♪
“媽媽，下雨了”
♪ Mommy, it's raining ♪
◎天在下紅色的雨◎
♪ it's raining red ♪
◎媽媽，天在下紅色的雨◎
♪ Mommy, it's raining red ♪
It；s溫熱；
It's warm'
為什麼這麼暖和？
Why is it warm?
[滴水的我
[Dripping I
Bx公司隱約可見4A…
Bx. Looms. 4A...
它正在發生
it's happening.
你妹妹會殺了我們 如果她知道我們是在她床上做的
Your sister would kill us if she knew we did it in her bed.
是的，是你的主意
Yeah, well, it was your idea.
我很壞，不是嗎？
I am bad, aren't I?
只有當你穿著 無襠內褲
Only when you wear crotchless panties
像狗一樣叫
and bark like a dog.
你要去哪裡？
Where are you going?
我要洗個澡
I gotta take a shower.
你知道，保持新鮮
You know, to stay fresh.
小心那個妖怪
Watch out for the Bogeyman.
嘿，貝絲，你能拿條毛巾來嗎 在這裡？我凍僵了！
Hey, Beth, can you bring a towel in here? I'm freezing!
你在哪？ 當我需要你的時候，親愛的？
Where are you when I need you, honey?
謝謝
Thanks.
我馬上就來
I'll be in in a minute.
媽媽？
Mommy?
等等，丹尼
Hold on a second, Danny.
丹尼，來找我
Danny, come to me.
-你好 -媽媽？
- Hello. - Mom?
等待這是誰？
Wait. Who is this?
不，我是貝絲
No, this is Beth.
你在那裡幹什麼？
What are you doing there?
你知道我媽媽在哪裡嗎？
Do you know where my mother is?
她不在家沒有人是
She's not home. No one is.
怎麼了？
What's wrong?
蒂姆和你在一起嗎？
Is Tim with you?
他在洗澡
He's in the shower.
我在街對面
I'm across the street.
我能看見你
I can see you.
貝絲，我要你聽我說
Beth, I want you to listen to me.
把蒂姆帶出去 就在這棟房子裡
Get Tim, and get out of that house right now.
卡拉，到底怎麼回事？
Kara, what the hell is going on?
貝絲，小心！ 房間裡有人！
Beth, look out! There's someone in the room!
他就在你後面！
He's right behind you!
不！
No!
不！丹尼，不！
No! Danny, no!
丹尼！
Danny!
丹尼
Danny.
媽媽
Mommy.
沒關係
It's okay.
丹尼，快跑！
Danny, run!
丹尼，到媽媽那兒來
Danny, come to Mommy.
丹尼，求你了
Danny, please.
哦！
Ohh!
來吧；
Come on'
孩子孩子在哪裡？
The baby. Where's the baby?
請開門！
Please, open the door!
求你了，有人幫幫我們！
Please, somebody help us!
請幫幫我們！
Help us, please!
快把他們帶上樓！
Get them upstairs now!
孩子在哪裡？
Where's the baby?
他走了
He's gone.
還有誰跪下生了孩子？
Who else knewl had the baby?
-沒有人 -沒有
- No one. - No.
一定有其他人！ 誰知道；？
There had to be someone else! Who knew'?
除了我和
Nobody knew, except me and...
丹尼，來找我
Danny, come to me.
來吧，丹尼來找我
Come, Danny. Come to me.
丹尼，不
Danny, no.
不，拜託
No. Please.
小心這個女孩
Careful with the girl.
卡拉！
Kara!
永利
Wynn.
布蘭肯希普太太 哦，天哪，快點
Mrs. Blankenship. Oh, God, hurry.
我們必須-
We have to-
你好，親愛的
Hello, dear.
她在哪裡？卡拉在哪裡？
Where is she? Where's Kara?
感覺我好像被下藥了
Feel like I've been drugged.
我們被下藥了
We have been drugged.
他們為什麼這麼做？
Why are they doing this?
為什麼他們不直接殺了我們？
Why didn't they just kill us?
這是他的遊戲
It's his game.
我知道 他想玩的地方
And I know where he wants to play it.
盧米斯醫生，你知道的 這阻止不了邁克爾
Dr. Loomis, you know that can't stop Michael.
沒有什麼能阻止邁克爾
Nothing will stop Michael...
但是永利
but Wynn...
我想在醫院告訴你
I tried to tell you in the hospital.
我想邁克爾在下面 邪惡符文的影響
I think Michael is under the influence of an evil rune.
索恩；
Thorn'
我看見那個符號標上了記號 我們發現傑米被刺傷了
I saw the symbol marked up where we found Jamie stabbed.
嗯，有光明符文， 保護
Well, there are runes of light, protection.
如果荊棘可以 被這些符文困住了，
If Thorn could somehow be trapped by these runes,
能量可以抵消 他們自己出來了，
the energies could cancel themselves out,
邪惡可以被摧毀
the evil could be destroyed.
你在這裡等著
You wait here.
不去任何地方 直到我回來
Don't go anywhere until I come back.
永利
Wynn.
是時候了，魯米斯醫生
About time, Dr. Loomis.
歡迎來到你的命運
Welcome to your fate.
時間到了 讓你知道真相
The time has come for you to know the truth.
時間到了 讓你加入我們
The time has come for you to join us.
為什麼是現在？
Why now?
傑米昨晚逃跑後， 我就知道她會來找你，
After Jamie escaped last night, I knew she would come to you,
我知道你 會帶我們找到她的孩子，
and I knew that you would lead us to her baby,
她非常特別的孩子
her very special baby.
我需要她 就像我現在需要你一樣
I needed her just as I need you now.
這是你的命運，山姆
It's your destiny, Sam.
我住在你體內
Ii lives inside you.
總是這樣
It always has.
你知道嗎，唐？
You know that, don't you?
你“…
You“...
3T9…
3T9...
瘋子；
a madman'
看看你周圍，山姆
Look around you, Sam.
到處都是瘋狂
Madness everywhere.
饑荒，戰爭，大瘟疫，
Famine, war, a great plague,
這些是跡象 我們必須恢復平衡
these are signs that we must restore balance
符合事物的自然規律
to the natural order of things.
我們只是提供手段
We merely provide the means.
邁克爾？
Michael?
我們給了他權力，
We've given him the power,
刺的禮物
the gift of Thorn.
我是它的拯救者
I am its deliverer.
我跟著它， 作為它的監護人
I follow it, act as its guardian.
我保護邁克爾， 小心他！
I protect Michael, watch over him!
現在是時候換一個了
And now it's time for another.
現在是你的時候了， 盧米斯醫生
Now it's time for you, Dr. Loomis.
我以為邁克爾是個怪物，
I thought Michael was a monster,
河口--
bayou--
哦！
Ohh!
把他留在那兒
Leave him there.
現在是他的辦公室
It's his office now.
精神和力量 火焰的
Spirits and powers of the flame...
參加並見證這個儀式
attend and witness this ritual.
把我們的禮物帶給索恩
Bear our gifts to Thorn.
打開我們的黑暗之路
Open us to the path of darkness.
通過這些符文，改變我們
By these runes, transform us.
讓錘子下降 在被選中的人身上
Let the hammer descend on the chosen one
我們把這個祭品獻給誰 無辜的鮮血
to whom we offer this sacrifice of innocent blood.
然後，丹尼， 你的旅程開始了
And then, Danny, yourjourney begins.
為他殺人；
Kill for him'
否
No.
邁克爾，你最後的犧牲
Michael, your final sacrifice.
邁克爾
Michael...
你可以讓他停下來
you can make him stop it.
不要殺了孩子
Don't kill the baby.
你可以阻止它
You can stop it.
你知道是誰的孩子， 不是嗎？
You know whose baby it is, don't you?
邁克爾！
Michael!
孩子是你的，不是嗎？
The baby is yours, isn't it?
是嗎，邁克爾？
Isn't it, Michael?
退後！
Back off!
把她解開！
Untie her!
照他說的做！做吧！
Do as he says! Do it!
你應該加入我們
You should join us.
你很有天賦
You have talent.
閉嘴
Shut up.
丹尼，來吧；
Danny, come on'
快走！
Go!
好的，走！
Okay, go!
快跑！
Run!
快走！
Go!
快走！快走！
Go! Go!
快走！快走！快走！
Move it! Go! Go!
倒楣！
Shit!
快點！
Come on!
-等等 -來吧；
- Wait. - Come on'
它不起作用！
It's not working!
它不工作！
It's--it's not working!
它不是…
It's not...
從門口退後！
Back up from the gates!
把他們弄出去！
Get 'em outta here!
進去！
Get in there!
繼續！當選！
Go on! Get in!
媽媽！
Mommy!
Samhain
Samhain'
湯米！他在哪裡？
Tommy! Where is he?
成功了
It worked.
符文的力量阻止了他
Power of the runes stopped him.
邁克爾
Michael...
他們對你做了什麼？
what have they done to you?
我們現在去哪裡？
Where do we go now?
離哈頓菲爾德很遠 盡可能的
As far away from Haddonfield as possible.
跟我們來
Come with us.
不，我——我有點事 來照顧這裡
No. I--I have a little business to attend to here.
邁克爾
Michael.
一切都結束了一切都結束了
It's all over. It's all over.
一切都結束了
It's all over.
邁克爾？
Michael?
米迦勒走了
Michael's gone.
現在是你的遊戲了，魯米斯醫生
It's your game now, Dr. Loomis.